What is going on guys? Welcome back to
the channel. This is Nikola right here.
Hope you guys are doing amazing.
So today I'm going to be showing you our
new interpolation tool for animations.
So you can find it either in creator,
you go [music] to tools, you go to
animate and besides the animate with
text new, you can find the interpolate
new.
>> [music]
>> Boom.
And that lets you add a first and last
frame
so you can animate a character or any
pixel art image. And it's also available
in A Sprite and [music] Pixelorama. So
you go to animate and you can find it
here at interpolate new.
And boom, you can set a start image and
an end image. [music] So I'm going to be
using the creator page just because here
we have a prompt [music] enhancer. In A
Sprite you won't be finding that. So
let's give it a try. So first we need a
character or something we're going to
work with so we can try [music] it out.
So let's make one.
A beautiful mage wearing a red robe
[music] using the create image pro tool.
All right, there we go.
All right, so let's try this. So the
first thing I'm going to do so we need a
first frame and a last frame. So I'm
going to try this. I'm going to go Okay,
so just to make it easy I'm going to go
ahead and use this one.
I'm going to go to A Sprite and
let's do the simplest example.
I'm going to get rid of this fireball
right here. I'm going to save it. Now
>> [music]
>> we're going to go to animate
interpolate. We're going to have this as
the last frame and we're going to have
this as the first frame. Now we're going
to describe the animation.
So
the mage [music] does a spell where a
fireball appears on her hands. So we can
try that.
Here we have the frame count. So
depending on the size you'll be able to
select how many frames your animation
will have.
The good thing about this model
same with the animate [music] with text
new
is that we can do a good amount of
frames. So for 64 by 64 we can do like
16 frames and for bigger sizes I think
128 by 128 you can also do 16. We'll
test it out in a bit.
And [music]
for 256 by 256 I think it's less, but
it's still a good amount. I think it's
like eight.
So let's try this out. I'm going to do
like what? 10 frames for this one.
And I'm not going to use the prompt
enhancer for this one just so we can see
how the [music] model
performs. All right, let's see what
happens. So we can see the frames.
>> [snorts]
>> Now let's see it playing.
Ooh, look at that. And of course we can
always download it. We can open it up in
A Sprite or in your software of
preference or either A Sprite,
Pixelorama or whatever.
And we can of course fix [music] some
details like this little detail that
just got removed. And there you go.
That's pretty awesome. So now let's try
it with the
prompt [music] enhancer. So I'm just
going to click enhance with AI and there
you go. We got a much better prompt. Now
I'm just going to click generate one
more time. Now let's check this one out.
All right, yep. So as you can see the
description matched. So as she
concentrates and she's actually
concentrating. We got some lighting as
well affecting the character which is
cool.
So yeah, that's the first test. All
right, so I got this cool dude that I
just made in 128 by 128
and I'm going to
go to edit image pro.
I'm going to drag it in here
and I'm going to say make it be the
first frame of the attack [music]
starting \slash} attack.
And I'm just going to hit generate. All
right, so that works. Let's try it to go
ahead and interpolate it. So we're going
to be using this other first frame and
this as our last frame. Just going to do
\slash} attack and I'm going to enhance
the prompt. [music] As you can see it
takes in the context of the actual image
you're giving it.
So I'm going to put the frame count to
10 and let's see how that goes.
Look at that.
That's pretty sick, not going to lie.
That's pretty cool. All right, so moving
on. You can also use it for walking
animations. So check this out.
If we take this awesome mage boom and
boom, we put it as first and last frame,
we can do a walking animation. Let's do
walking with hair flowing, right?
Let's enhance the prompt. There you go.
Pretty nice prompt. And let's do like
um
>> [snorts]
>> yeah, eight eight frames. Let's do it.
All right, so let's check it out. Look
at that.
Look at that. It just froze for one
frame because I mean we can we can just
delete that one frame, but we have a
full walking animation. Look at that.
That's amazing. So of course we can
clean it up like I said.
Always
clean your sprites up.
I say this in every video and I'm going
to keep saying it.
Don't expect it to be 100% perfect. But
hey, we got 95%
No, 99% of the way there. Look at that.
Who's even talking?
And of course you can edit that out. You
can change the mouth. You can change
whatever. But look at that beautiful
walking animation with the hair flowing
and everything.
Whoa, just whoa. All right, let's try
another use case. Transformations. Check
this out. So I have my first frame which
is a car and my last frame which is like
a Transformers version of it. I'm going
to prompt the car [music] transforms
into a Transformers like figure. I'll
enhance the prompt
and hit generate.
And look at that. That's what I call a
Transformers.
One more Transformers for you guys. This
one in 256 by 256. So here we get eight
frames. I'll prompt the Transformers
turns back into a car [music] and
enhance the prompt.
And check it out. Pretty neat. Of course
you can go to edit in Pixelorama right
here and edit your sprites, clean them
up or even reduce colors with our reduce
colors tool using your own palette or
just reducing the amount of colors in
the images. All right, so now let's try
it out in A Sprite. So same thing.
Here we have first and last frame.
We go to the animate category.
We find interpolate new.
>> [music]
>> There we go. And we put our start image
and our end image.
There we go. Now we can just prompt
something like
um
the chest rumbles and
opens.
I don't know.
Let's try it out. I'm going to put it
right here. New frame, remove the
background and hit generate.
All right, it's the moment of truth.
Let's see. Yeah, exactly what I asked
for.
>> [music]
>> The chest rumbled. I'm just going to
make it a little bit slower.
Look at that. Yeah, and of course
clean it up. Boom.
Boom. There we go. Yeah. And of course
you can shorten it, you know, or you can
ask for less frames. I asked for a bunch
of frames just for this simple
animation,
but you can ask for less frames or you
can of course pick and choose, you know,
like we don't have to have all of this
happening at the same time. So I can
just
you know, shorten it a bit. Let's see.
Let's see.
See?
And yep, there you go.
Awesome. So to end this video I'm going
to try a nice portal. I have this nice
empty portal and I'm going to go to the
inpaint tool and I'm going to prompt a
really cool portal. Now I'm just going
to paint on the inpainting layer where I
want the portal to appear, hit remove
background and click generate. And there
we go. That's beautiful. So with this
I'm going to head to the interpolation
tool and I'm going to set the first and
last frame. I'm going to prompt a
magical portal activates [music]
showing the universe. And let's do 12
frames for this one.
And look at that. Amazing.
Let's do one last test. Let's take this
frame and set it as the first frame as
well so we can try and loop the portal.
I'll prompt a magical portal loops
showing the universe loop animation and
hit generate.
And yeah, that's pretty awesome if I say
so myself. So, that's our new
interpolate tool and it's live on our
website Aseprite and Pixelorama. Make
sure to check it out and share your
creations with us.