In this video, I'm going to show you a
few different ways to make walking
animations or walk cycles for your
characters in Pixel Lab. First, I'm here
on the Pixel Lab website, and this is
the characters page where you can make
characters in the character creator. We
already have a video covering the
character creator, so make sure to check
that out if you haven't yet. That one
doesn't really cover the pro mode,
though, so in this video, I'm going to
show a bit of that, too. Here you've got
a few different options. You can prompt
a character from scratch and generate it
with text. You can import your own
character if you already made one and
then either rotate it with Pixel Lab or
animate it. And if you already have the
rotations, you can also import those and
just focus on the animation side. If
you're using Pro, you can also give it a
concept image and have it generate a
pixel art character based on that
reference, which is what I'm going to do
here. So, I'm going to drop in this
concept image of a man wearing a green
hoodie, blue jeans, and a baseball hat.
And I'm going to generate him as a low
top- down character at 56 pixels.
All right. Now that we've got our
character generated, you can see there's
a button here that says add your first
animation. If we click that, we get the
full list of animation templates that
are available. In this case, I'm going
to choose walking. And you can see we
have a pretty good amount of different
walking animation options here, but I'm
going to go with walking six frames. You
can also choose which direction you want
to animate first. So, I'm going to pick
southeast.
And there we go. We already got a pretty
decent result. Of course, from here, we
can go into Pixelorama, clean things up,
make edits, and get it looking more
polished. So, that's exactly what I'm
going to do. I'm opening this up in
Pixelarama and I'm also opening the
eight rotations we have of the
character. The reason I'm doing that is
because the face in the rotation sheet
is cleaner than the one in the animation
frames. I'm going to clean up the
rotations to my liking just to make sure
I have the perfect character. I'm going
to copy the face from the rotations and
paste it into the walking animation
frames so I can get a much cleaner and
more consistent head.
As you can also see, the backpack is
kind of changing size a little bit too
much from frame to frame. So, I'm going
to quickly copy one of the better
backpack shapes and paste it across the
frames just to make it feel more
coherent and less like it's morphing.
And once that cleanup is done, you can
go back to the character page, press
refresh, and there it is, all updated.
Now, from here, you can, of course,
generate all the other directions, too.
And that's what I'm going to do now. I'm
just going to click the rocket icon to
generate the rest. There we go.
Something really useful here is that if
you made, for example, a southeast
animation, then in the southwest slot,
you'll get a new button that lets you
mirror the animation.
So, if you already have a really good
southeast animation and you want the
opposite direction quickly, you can just
click mirror and it'll fill that
direction with the flipped version of
the animation.
That's super useful if your character is
symmetrical enough for that to work. But
if your character has different details
on each side, for example, one sleeve is
long and the other one is short, or
there's a bag strap only on one side, or
hair that falls differently, then of
course you probably don't want to flip
it because it'll look wrong. So, in this
case, I'm going to do the same cleanup
process again. I'm going back to the
character rotations, grabbing those
cleaner heads, and pasting them into the
walking animations so there's more
consistency across directions. And this
is something you can do with other
animations too. But I think for walking
it's especially important and also
pretty easy because the movement isn't
too extreme. A lot of the time it's just
about placing the head correctly and
keeping the design clean. So that right
there is option one for making a walk
cycle for your character. Now option two
would be using a sprite or pixelama
together with the animate with skeleton
tool. This one is really powerful, but
it is a bit more complex than just
pressing a button and saying animate.
Here, the process is more like rigging
your character. You're basically giving
the model a skeleton to work with. And
you do that by clicking the set
reference button.
So, first you choose the correct camera
view depending on the perspective of
your character.
Then we go into edit skeleton. We select
the reference direction and then the
template style depending on the kind of
character we have. There's stuff like
bipeedal, realistic, chibi, and
quadripeds. Then we choose the animation
template, and I'm going to pick walk six
frames. You can also adjust things like
the skeleton height, the head size, and
even offset the skeleton if you need to,
but usually the model does a pretty good
job of keeping things in place. Once
everything looks good, you click insert
template. And as you can see, it adds
the new animation poses into the frames
automatically.
So now the next step is generating those
frames. This process is slower than the
first option because here you can only
generate two frames at a time, but the
results can be really nice, so I'd say
it's definitely worth it if you want
more control.
What you're seeing here is the reference
image which is our character and then
you have the frozen frame which
basically gives the model context for
what's already happening in the
animation. So the model is using that as
a reference point to continue the motion
into the next poses. You can either
freeze one frame and generate two frames
or freeze two frames and generate one
frame if you want to give the model even
more context.
So, I hit generate.
And as you can see, we already have a
really solid start. Sometimes you'll
notice little things shift. For example,
the colors in the eyes might change
slightly. So, what I'm going to do here
is just copy the eyes from the original
frame and paste them into the generated
ones so they stay consistent. Then I
keep going, generate the next two
frames, paste the eyes again, and repeat
that until the full six frame walk cycle
is done. And you can see it gives us a
pretty nice walking animation. Now I'm
going to try another direction. Let's do
southeast. I insert the template there.
I'm going to change the direction. I'm
going to go to edit skeleton. I'm going
to change the reference direction as
well. I'm going to insert the animation
template. And there we go. Now I'm just
going to start generating. And of
course, just like before, you can clean
everything up. Make sure it looks right
to your eye. And keep generating two
frames at a time.
That cleanup step matters because
remember every frame you accept becomes
context for the next one. So if your
current frames are messy, the following
frames can get messier too. So for
example here, I'm just going to copy the
head and paste it into each frame so the
colors stay stable and everything looks
more consistent.
Now, the third option is using animation
to animation. And this one is great if
you already have a walking animation
from another character or from a
template. So, here I already have a
walking animation template ready. I'm
going to open the animation to animation
tool. What this tool does is basically
transfer the motion and shape structure
of an existing animation onto a new
character. You first choose how many
frames you want to use. Depending on the
size of your sprite, the maximum can
vary, but in this case with a 64x 64
canvas, we can go up to nine frames, and
that's perfect because this animation
has eight frames. Then we've got the
description field. For this example, I'm
going to prompt an old man wearing a
Hawaiian shirt. For the action
description, I'm just going to put
walking. For the camera view, I'm going
to choose low, top down, facing south.
Then you have things like outline,
details, and shading, which basically
control how detailed and stylized the
character ends up looking. You can also
set a target palette if you want, but
I'm not going to do that here.
And there we go. Now, just a bit of a
cleanup, remove some stray pixels, and
we have a perfect walking animation with
our new character.
And finally, if you have a character
with really similar shapes, you can use
it as a reference. Here I have my monk
and I'll use it as a reference. So I'll
click use reference image and set
reference. I'll edit the description to
a bald monk. And I'll even do it with
the old man as the base.
So those are three different ways to
make walking animations in Pixel Lab.
The first option is the fastest and
easiest if you just want to generate a
walk cycle directly inside the character
workflow. The second option using
animate with skeleton gives you more
control and can get you really nice
results if you don't mind doing a bit
more setup. And the third option
animation to animation is perfect if you
already have a motion template and want
to transfer that movement onto a new
character. So depending on your project
and how much control you want, you can
pick whichever workflow makes the most
sense. If this video helped you out,
make sure to like, subscribe, and check
out the other Pixel Lab tutorials on the
channel.