Hi guys, welcome to today's tutorial. In
this video, we're going to cover how to
use create isometric tile. Up top, we
have tile shape. You can use the dropown
to select the type of tile you'd like.
There are a couple of options, thick,
thin, block, and reference. There's also
none.
when you select them, the top area here
uh changes.
[Music]
For this tutorial, we'll be using
reference shape, and you can set and
clear the reference. What the reference
image does is tell the model what shape
the tile should be and also some
information on u shading and stuff like
that.
And underneath we have the description.
This is where you tell the model what
the tile should look like.
It doesn't need to be a simple
description.
You can add more detail if you like.
And just make sure it's uh something
that you want your tile to look like and
get creative.
Then we have outline, shading, and
details. You can select the options you
want. Feel free to try them out and
figure out which settings works best for
your project. Tile size, there is 32x
32, 16x 16 and other. So depending on
your canvas size, select the one that
fits you best.
Then we have init image, which helps
define shape and appearance. If you have
it higher, it will look more like your
init image. And if it's lower, uh, it
will look less like it. And you can play
around and see what works best in your
case.
Just make sure it looks uh more like
your end result cuz that's what it will
uh push the model towards.
Then in advanced options we have
guidance weight which will push the
model to make the generated image look
more or less like your text description.
It also impacts outline shading and
details and like how uh much color there
is.
And down here we have load previous
settings where you can find your
previous seeds for old generations.
And yeah, that's uh pretty much it. So
let's go ahead and generate our first
isometric tile.
I'm just going to
put back the default settings and click
generate.
And here we have it, our first tile. I'm
just going to make some quick fixes to
it.
And here I'm just reducing the number of
colors in the uh image.
[Music]
Same way as before. I'm just creating a
water on top of dirt.
Just going to fix it up a bit. Then we
will start creating the map.
[Music]
So when creating a uh tile map with
isometric tiles, you want to stack them
together like this. Then you can copy
paste to make it faster once you have
some tiles already in place. For those
of you who are making a video game, this
is usually done programmatically. But
since this is just a quick tutorial, I'm
just doing it by hand instead.
[Music]
And now to make it a bit prettier, let's
uh create some trees and stuff to have
in our map. So in this case I'm using
the pixlux model to generate the tree
but you can also use extend map on the
map that you have like I did in the
previous tutorials.
[Music]
If you have any questions, Feel free to
leave a comment or join the Discord
channel and ask us there.
We usually respond within minutes, maybe
an hour or so, so it's a lot more
efficient than YouTube comments. Thank
you for watching and I will see you next
time.