We just released a new object creator
page on our website. Here's how it
works. Prompt any object you want or
prompt a pack of assets and get a full
group of objects that fit your game.
Choose the size of your objects with the
slider. You can choose style references
from your object creator gallery if
you've made projects before with the map
editor, or you can drag your own assets
as style images and just hit generate.
Once the assets are generated, you can
select which objects you want to keep,
tag, delete. Next, if you're not using a
style reference, you can choose the
perspective of the objects. So, either
top down or sidescroller. And you can
also describe each item you want in this
drop- down list. If you leave it empty,
it'll make what you asked in your
prompt.
Here's an example for sidescroller as
well.
Another thing you can do is create an
object with eight directions. So, a
fully rotated object. Let's try that
with this king throne. Of course, you
can choose the camera view and hit
generate and check it out. Pretty cool.
Here are the last two things I want to
show you. When you go inside of an
object page, you can create new states
of that object. If you hit create state,
you can edit that object and get another
variation. Basically, for example, I'll
prompt dirty. And here you can see the
dirty faucet. The last thing is
animations. Here you can click add your
first animation. Here you have two
options. You can use the animation pro
model or the animation V3 model. They
perform differently and they cost
different generation amounts so you can
choose which tool you want to use. You
can also enhance your prompt so the
model has a stronger output.
That's the object creator. Thank you for
watching. Make sure to let us know how
it goes with your usage of it and share
your creations on the Discord.