hi in this video I will show you our
plugin in the free pixel art editor
pixel Rama which can be run in the
browser in this video I will go through
how to generate a character how to
rotate your character how to create
animations and how to use in painting to
add equipment I will timestamp the
different parts so if there's anything
in particular you're interested in you
can skip ahead to that part so to start
off let's create a character so here I
have chosen create medium to extra large
image which is our flux
model so if you hover over a certain um
setting you can see there is a hint
which is something that is visible in
pix but not in a Sprite so that's a good
thing to know
so I'm thinking let's create a female
Merchant in
a brown
dress and we want to uh remove the
background and once we're happy with the
settings we uh click generate
all right we have our character so I'm
just going to select the pette
instead and now I want to show you
reduce
colors so here I have automatic but you
can also select um how many colors you
want and uh you can also select your
palette instead and it just
basically uh removes any artifacts where
it's like lots of different colors which
is quite
nice and I'm just going to clean up the
Sprite real quick and then we will move
on to uh the rotation tool
so sometimes when you generate you might
not get the uh direction that you
wanted so to fix that uh you can use the
rotate tool to uh yeah fix the direction
or the view if you're unhappy with that
it doesn't it's not always an issue but
if it is it's uh good thing to know that
you can always do it afterwards so here
I'll go from Southwest to South which I
believe is like the position my
character is standing in and then
remember to set your from image and yeah
just click
generate now you have a couple of
options either you could manually which
I'm doing right here uh fix up any
things that you think should be
different or you could use this
uh uh new character as a init image and
just let the model uh generate a new
character but based on the correct uh
Direction and view
now I want to uh generate my characters
are looking to the
West instead so all I do is the same
thing but now I want my two direction to
be West
instead and yeah that's all you need to
do to rotate your
character I will just quickly clean up
my image a bit and then we will move on
to the next thing which is how you can
generate
animations some shortcuts I recommend
learning are P for pencil tool M to move
around or the uh scroll
button e for erase and O to pick colors
when you're happy with your character
and you think it's time to uh create
some animations you can go over to
animate with skeleton the first thing
you want to do is to uh create a
skeleton
template so here I am setting my
character as the
reference and what's nice with the pixel
Rama is that there's this tool on the
right side which is the same as edit
skeleton which just allows you to uh
move the
points and the shortcut is
G uh for edit
skeleton and here I just want to make
sure that the uh the skeleton
is as good as possible so once we uh
insert the template it will be at the
like highest quality you might still
want to go through the template and uh
move some points if you feel like it's
necessary
it's not like incredibly important that
the points are perfect but the better
you make them like the better the
quality of your uh generation will be uh
so I'm
thinking we can do
um walk uh four frames just to quickly
show you how it's done uh remember to uh
change the template
Direction so it faces the same direction
as your
character and
uh yeah here I
insert without uh forcing the
head like the head points which has a
tendency to um negatively impact the uh
the quality of the face of your
character so here I'm just going to
force it instead and now you can see
like the uh the head the points of the
head is like stays the
same and similar to um my previous
tutorial I will start off by freeze one
generate two
frames I will link that tutorial as well
but it's in aprite instead done I hope
that uh everything is basically the same
but uh there have been a few small
changes but the the thinking is the
same all right nice
since we are since we will be generating
the future frames based on these frames
I highly recommend trying to uh clean up
the images a bit before generating the
next frame because if these are bad they
will have a yeah negative impact on
future
Generations so the better that you make
them the better the next frame will be
so now I will do freeze two and generate
one frame and I positioned myself on the
eighth frame so eighth and the ninth
frames are like reference images which
will help the model understand what the
next frame will look
like but as you can see in this
uh generated oh yeah I'm just going to
fix this
first so here I take the hand that I
likeed more in
the other frame and uh add it to this
Frame as
well and um yeah just fixing the size a
bit but yeah as you can see like the uh
the arm is the same as in the eighth
frame and it's supposed to be the
opposite so here I'm just going to be
using in painting and uh in it image to
help the model understand which arm
should behind and in front of
which which is like a very powerful tool
to uh yeah make the model do what you
want uh thankfully it did the legs
correctly so here I'm just inating so I
went over to the in painting layer and
now I am wherever I draw now is where
the model can
edit and just for you guys uh e is the
arrays o is like picking the color and P
is for like the pencil tool and here you
can see um I click in use in painting
and you can see like in the UI it's
black which means that's where it's
going to edit
oh yeah I forgot in it image all
right if you don't use uh in it image
the model won't uh be able to see what's
underneath the in painting so don't
forget to toggle that
on all right as you can see we got our
arm correctly placed there and here I'm
just copy pasting the
hair because I kind of liked it that it
was longer which was why I kept it and
for the last
image we don't need in painting we don't
need a init image we just do like we did
the previously we position ourselves on
the ninth frame so the ninth and 10th
Frame will be like reference so the
model will have
more knowledge and understanding when
generating the 11th
frame or that's like the fourth frame in
the animation
all right we have our frames so now I'm
just going
to tag this so that I can show you what
the animation uh looks
like so I'm selecting all the four
frames new
tag then if you right click and you go
to uh properties you can change like the
frame duration so it's it's not like
super
fast and then uh on the right here you
can click uh
play all right there's some color
changes which isn't perfect but as the
tool becomes better I think when this is
released we will have made another
update to animate skeleton so hopefully
it will be even
better uh but yeah
now I want to show you the in
painting so remember to go over to the
in painting layer and here I forgot to
make it visible so I can't draw in it
and just draw where you want to in
paint and here I am showing
the like the current in painting tool
but we also have a the experimental one
which I will show after so yeah just
remember to uh inpaint in the in
painting
layer and you will see that it shows up
as like black in the UI where it will
draw all
right let's
uh go over to the experimental one I
think this also has had an update since
I did this tutorial Things Are
always changing you know getting
better and I can reuse the same in
painting and I forgot to change it to
new frame you can use new layer as well
but I think it's easier for
demonstration that we create a new frame
instead for
I'm not super happy with the results so
let's uh try again and see if uh it does
better on a second try
and yeah I think that looks better so
remember it's always worth to uh try
again and see if it does better the
second time
so yeah I hope you found this helpful
and useful if you have any questions
feel free to ask them here or preferably
in Discord so you can share an image of
what you're struggling with and we can
uh give you some input and tips on how
to uh get the tools to uh to do what you
want and yeah I will see you in the next
video