hi today I'll be showing our new tool
called generate image that can use a
style
image so what's great about this tool is
the new style image so what it allows
you to do is use a image that you have
and generate new images that looks
similar to that image in
style so to use style image you just
select style image here and then let's
uh say we want to make a breastplate
armor uh what's good to note is that
when generating using a style image the
model likes to use the colors found in
the image so it's good if the uh the
thing that you're trying to generate
uses the same colors as your style image
it's not necessary but it's it makes it
a bit better for the
model
now the image here is a bit small and
the reason for that is I had image size
20 so let's increase that a bit let's
say we want a Sprite that is 48 in size
instead all right so once we generated
something we can use use in painting to
change the image but not the whole image
so for example if we like a certain part
of the image but we would change other
parts we can in paint the areas that we
want to change in this case let's say I
want this uh plate armor to be
completely
steel so
I can just inpaint this part right
here and the model can only change this
part of the
image nice and then we can
actually continue this if for example
let's say you're not happy with this
part and you want to try and see if you
can do better can in paint that and
generate
again and
yeah
the generate image style is quite
versatile it's best used for characters
and
objects here you can see some examples
of what I've
done um so in this case I started off
with this um couch and created the this
table using this as a style image the
couch that's
aage uh for the equipment here I had my
sword which I created an Axe and I
created these uh plate mail armors from
The Sword as
well uh I also created this lantern from
this
sword let's create a character so I'm
going to use style image
again and I'm just going to start off by
having view side because my character is
side character and then I want a
character that's facing the
South and if you don't like what you get
you can just
retry and if you get something that
is acceptable you can then come back in
and make some uh edits to fix the image
so let's do it that way so I'm going to
use in pinning here to uh let's say
uh let's fix the um the hair
maybe let's fix the face in general
um let's say we want a
female
mage
laer
and then we can
do another fix and when we're using in
painting we can just edit a certain part
of the image which is quite
nice so we don't need to worry that
we're ruining something
else
and yeah this
is a bit of a iterative
process where you make some changes you
go back in make some more
changes and then uh until you're
happy and we can do uh
maybe Mage holding a fireball
could be pretty cool and then we can
just in paint here where we like our
Fireball to be so let's say it should be
here and then
if we just do it like this it will we
can't really control it exactly what we
want so instead we can also go in
here add some red and give like a um
maybe like a shape of the
Fireball and then we can use a init
image just to like show the model where
we want the fireball to be and kind of
uh what it should look
like go
back can take
this
maybe we want to
uh extend it a bit so let's do
that
and we can um because we like this
Fireball a bit more so we can increase
the strength a bit just to keep the
original
Fireball
and
maybe we would like to give her a a nice
hat we can do
that let's say we want to
uh give her a hat give her a hat a
female Mage wearing a wizard hat maybe
you should give it a bit more
room
that hat is quite big so what we could
do
is can take the
Hat maybe downsize it a
bit put it back
on
and
then we could uh maybe add some sh shoes
to our
character so we can do something like
this uh
[Music]
female
let's do a par
boots let's try
without let's I think we might need an
in image here so I'm just going to go in
here
and just add
something so the model understands where
the Boost boost should
be
nice
beautiful so yeah now we G through all
everything you can pretty much do with
the uh generate image tool I hope this
is helpful and uh will increase your
productivity some things to note here in
the advanced
options have a style guidance
weight which will
uh influence how much the uh style image
will affect the generation so a higher
style guidance will mean it will look
more like the uh the style
image and when it comes to guidance
weight here for the description and
everything this affects all of these
categories uh all these
settings and the init image strength
higher means it will look more like the
init image and lower means that it would
uh look less and what this actually is
is like decides the starting point of
the
generation so for
example if you have one it just kind of
sees the shape I guess and if it's 999
it means that the image it will do
nothing to the image pretty
much um
yeah