hi in today's video I will show you how
you can generate a punching animation
with our skeleton tool so first let's
generate a
character so what could be more fitting
than uh generating a boxer so I'm going
to use the generate generate character
tool and ask for a male boxer in red
shorts
all right nice now I want to show you
what happens if you change like outline
shading and
details uh which will uh affect the uh
style of the character that's
generated so here you can see a much
more realistic looking
character and if you make it even more
Det until it will be even more uh
realistic so this is some new settings
for our new uh generate character and uh
style
tool I recommend trying different
outlines and shadings and stuff just to
see what works and here I'm just
generating the rotation for my
character I'm not super happy with the
placement of the right hand glove so I'm
just going to move it over over edit
edit the image a bit then use it as my
init
image the init image will help tell the
model where the glove should be as it's
like a starting point for the model now
that we have our character uh let's uh
create some animations so first I will
estimate skeleton which will give me a
skeleton for my character then I'm just
going to edit a bit to make sure it's uh
it fits my character better
so this is pretty important to do
because if you're going to insert
skeleton uh the skeleton that you have
in your uh in your frame is going to
affect the uh what the insert a skeleton
is going to look like because it's based
on that
one and yeah don't worry we we will do
this uh two more times with uh the other
characters that you saw in the
beginning so but yeah so this is also me
learning how to do this as we
go uh I had I I haven't really done this
before so it's uh always
fun so here I'm just removing the uh
last two frames because I wasn't super
happy with them and I'm going to Ed this
edit this frame a little bit so I'm
going to use this Frame and the first
frame you generated as like a guidance
for the model so I'm going to generate
the last two frames
again and this helps the model get a
better understanding of what it's trying
to
do because it has more information to go
from and yeah quite nice this glove
needs a little bit of editing so I'm
going to give it some
love uh first I thought of moving the
AR but I felt like ah let's just move
the uh skeleton instead so I'm going in
here add a
skeleton and then just moving the bone
or the point a bit and therefore the
arm and then remember to go back to the
first
frame in the animation and then generate
all right now let's do the same for our
more realistic
boxer so I will quickly
generate my
rotation and then I will uh get
started so first fix my settings then
estimate skeleton like
before edit the skeleton so it fits my
character better
here the biggest mistake is probably
like the neck is in the wrong
place and I'm just going to first edit
the uh
arms and
shoulders and you can see like the small
UI dialogue there uh What uh bone or
point is selected so here for example it
says
neck and then once you're happy can
insert
skeleton in this case I'm not going to
delete one of the uh one of the
frames and yeah I just click
generate so yeah it's kind of lost the
uh the boxing glove but that's actually
quite easy to for us to just
manually uh fix and you could do this
with init image uh as well and just um
draw like a red blob or something but I
think in this case it's probably just
easier to copy paste the glove
around and the gloves that I'm copy
pasting around could also be used used
as a init image as well so whether you
use whether you draw it or you just copy
paste it uh it will give the same
effect now I wasn't super happy with the
last frame so similar to last time I'm
going to edit the skeleton a
bit uh what's good to know is the last
point that you touch with the edit tool
is what's closest to uh like to us so to
fix the like said index I want to move
the uh right arm
last so here still it got a little bit
confused it probably would have been
better to move in the left arm even
further but still this is so easy to fix
I'm just going to use the erase tool and
remove that uh St
or and yeah all
good and now we have a punching
animation so now for the last character
I'm going to take my 64x 64 character
and use it as a init
image so this will just help the model
understand like this size and what my
character should look like
pretty good I must say so I'm just going
to fix up the uh colors a bit if you can
even call it that maybe I'm just
actually making it less good by Ed
now when it's time to generate my
animation I'm just going to use the
knowledge that I learned so first
estimate skeleton then I'm going to edit
the uh the pose a bit to make it fit my
character
better and then I will insert the
skeleton
things that should be good to note is
that
we like the hand doesn't need doesn't
need to be at the edge of the hand but a
bit up but it shouldn't be super
important and what you will see here is
because
my uh skeleton
is isn't perfect for the uh the template
that we have for this
animation I need to uh move the uh bones
a
bit so I'm moving it closer to the neck
just to make the uh the arm uh
shorter still it's not perfect so at
this point I'm just going to go in and
edit it by hand it just it only takes
like one second so it's it's fine to to
do the these small details by hand in my
opinion then here I'm just going to move
out the arm a bit because as we
previously noted it's it's a bit too
short
and just like
before I think like okay last frame is
good first frame is good second frame is
all right so I'm going to do is I'm just
going to copy paste over the hand of
course I could use init image and in
painting and do this with the model
instead but in this case I feel like
it's so easy to just edit it by hand so
I'm going to do that
instead and now we have like first
second and the fourth frame uh
already created so now we only need to
generate uh this third
frame and here I can I can see the small
changes I need to do to make this
perfect so I'm just going to edit it by
hand and yeah it's done I hope you
enjoyed the video leave a like and uh
comment if you have any questions and
feel free to join the Discord if you
need uh more support