All right. So, let me show you one of
the most powerful tools in Pixelab right
now.
>> Create image from style reference.
>> This tool is all about consistency.
If you've ever generated assets that
look cool but don't look like they
belong in the same game, well, this
fixes that. Instead of prompting style
every time, you teach Pixel App a visual
style using reference images and then
generate new assets [music] that match
it.
So, first things first, when you open
the tool, Pixel Lab asks you for a
canvas size [music] unless you already
have a open canvas. This part is
extremely important because the canvas
size directly controls how many frames
you get. So, if you choose 32x 32 or 16x
16, you get up to 64 frames.
>> [music]
>> That means you can upload up to 64
reference images and Pixel Lab [music]
will generate 64 new assets. Now, you
don't need all 64. [music] Honestly,
with 5 to 10 good images, the results
are already really solid. If you choose
64x 64, the frame limit drops to 16. So,
that's 16 reference images max [music]
and 16 outputs. With 128x 128, you get
four frames [music] total. And at 256 x
256, you're generating a single image
with just one reference [music] image.
So the rule is simple. Smaller
resolution equals more style learning
and bigger resolution equals more
precision. Now, let's talk about the
most important part, [music] style
images. So up here you'll see style
images. 0 out of 64. This is where you
upload your references. These can be
characters, weapons, icons, props,
anything [music] you want to match
stylistically. The key thing here is
consistency. You want [music] similar
pixel density, similar outlines, similar
shading, [music] and similar
proportions. Basically, you're showing
Pixel app. This is the visual language
that I want. [music] And again, you
don't need a ton. Five to 10 references
work better than 60 random ones. Next is
the description field. This is not where
you [music] describe the style because
the style already comes from the images.
So here you describe what you want to
generate. For example, medieval weapons,
small slime enemies, [music]
fantasy character faces, or I don't
know, magic potions and items. Think of
it like giving instructions to a pixel
[music] artist and not really writing a
prompt. Under output settings, I usually
keep it simple. Set the output method to
new layer. Turn remove background on so
everything stays transparent and you
should be good to go. Now, when you hit
generate, [music] Pixel Lab creates
multiple frames. What you're getting
here is basically an instant asset pack.
You design the style once and then just
scale it. And that's really the magic of
this tool. If you want to try it
yourself, go check it [music] out at
pixelab.ai.
Make sure to leave a like, comment, and
subscribe.