hi I would like to show you our latest
tool create character onot it allows you
to both generate a character with
rotations animations from scratch but
also generate rotations and animations
for your existing
characters if you want to generate a
character from sketch you can leave the
south east and north image empty if you
want to generate based on your existing
characters set your character to the
corresponding image
uh currently there are two animations a
walking animation and a attacking
animation in the future I will be adding
more currently I'm thinking maybe a
spellcasting animation and some special
effects like a fireball and also running
animation but of course join the Discord
and uh uh give suggestions maybe some
like mining animations could be
fun uh
other things I will be uh looking to
implement after a bit of testing is 128
by 128 image size support and also all
eight uh directions like Southeast
Northeast and
Etc something that is good to knowe is
that when you're generating quadrupedal
at the moment uh sometimes the start
image is a bit yeah it doesn't perfectly
follow follow that the direction so you
can just uh click try again until it's
like Facing East uh for the first image
and then just double check that the next
image is facing south and the last one
is facing north if it doesn't work just
click try again and hopefully after like
two tries it will uh do it
correctly but yeah don't forget there's
also the animate with text and animate
with skeleton which you can use to
create your own things as well uh to
create the yeah your own animations and
your own touch you can also use animate
with skeleton to edit the generations
you see here so if you think like the
arm should move a bit more forward you
can estimate skeleton move it a bit and
then just generate a improved version on
your own
[Music]
no a
all right let's go through how to use
your character as a reference so set the
corresponding image for the that
direction and you can check the UI to
make sure that it's correct and once
you're happy just double check the
camera view and you can click generate
and off you go
[Music]
n
uh yeah thank thank you for watching I
hope you have fun trying out the Tool uh
if you have any suggestions or like
improvements or things you would like to
see feel free to leave a comment here in
the YouTube channel or joining the
Discord and uh give suggestions in the
feedback uh Channel and yeah I will see
you in the next video